<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-16T02:37:54-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">97115104’s blog</title><subtitle>A simple, content-focused blog detailing musings.</subtitle><author><name>97115104</name></author><entry><title type="html">hodl? lol. not here.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/holdl-lol-not-here/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hodl? lol. not here." /><published>2025-06-25T01:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T01:30:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/holdl-lol-not-here</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/25/holdl-lol-not-here/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-i-killed-my-own-crypto-project-and-built-something-that-could-actually-live">why i killed my own crypto project (and built something that could actually live)</h2>

<p>I built Health Protocol thinking if you gave people privacy, incentives, and proof, everything would just work. I shipped the infra and wrote the math with Claude’s help. I modeled every outcome using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monte_Carlo_method">Monte Carlo sims</a>. Every time, the same ending. Whales won, bots drained the pool, real users quit. The DAO was a graveyard. Nothing felt new. It was the same fate as every corporate wellness app, insurance “incentive,” and NFT move-to-earn. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/11qaopr/the_end_of_stepn_and_why_public_are_confused/">STEPN</a> made you buy $1,200 sneakers for a shot at a token jackpot. By the end, bots were farming, prices tanked, and most users left holding nothing but another Discord full of bad memes.</p>

<p>I did the research. I looked at everything: DeFi, behavioral econ, read <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Dawkins">Richard Dawkins</a> and thought about how casinos and governments try to buy good behavior. None of them solved the core problem: how do you reward people for what actually matters and keep privacy as a non-negotiable? The old Health Protocol yellowpaper documented exactly how it would fail.</p>

<h2 id="arishem-eternals-and-building-for-life-not-stasis">arishem, eternals, and building for life, not stasis</h2>

<p>The moment I gave up on the old protocol was sometime after midnight, Marvel’s Eternals on in the background, Arishem explaining why universes are born to die and recycle. It clicked. The problem wasn’t just incentives, it was immortality: THE VAMPIRE PARADOX! If you build for stasis, the system probably gets gamed and dies a boring death. If you build for life with decay, adaptation, feedback, etc, then it turns out you get a protocol that might actually live forever. <a href="https://marvelcinematicuniverse.fandom.com/wiki/Arishem">Arishem</a>: cosmic midwife, blockchain muse.</p>

<h2 id="value-that-vanishes-and-the-birth-of-the-reservoir">value that vanishes, and the birth of the reservoir</h2>

<p>Every protocol I looked at was built on the same dead logic: make a token, freeze value, pray nobody dumps. That doesn’t work. Real biological systems move. In Autophage, tokens decay. You can’t save indefinitely though Wellness Vaults (think HSAs but on-chain) are a thing. You either have to use tokens you earn right away or set them aside for specific goals like how college funds and HSAs work, and if you ghost, your balance fades out.</p>

<p>The first person who called this out as bullshit was my mom. She said, “money isn’t supposed to disappear.” I tried to explain decay, game theory, and why hoarding ruins incentives. She said, “let it all flow back to everyone else, like a reservoir.” She was right so that’s exactly what I built; the missing piece. <strong>The Reservoir</strong> collects all decayed tokens and recycles them as system fuel. It pays future rewards, covers healthcare payouts, and backs the protocol’s safety net. My mom named it, shout-out to you Momma!</p>

<p>So you earn tokens, those tokens decay at different rates depending on how you earned them, i.e., through what exercise or activity. You can spend them lots of ways, but if you don’t they simply return to The Reservoir, funding other people’s health emergencies or yours. The Reservoir remembers 100% of the value you contribute through token decay and works like how “social security” is supposed to, except it doesn’t run out and is USDC backed through platform and marketplace fees.</p>

<h2 id="game-the-system-then-evolve">game the system, then evolve</h2>

<p>You earn tokens as mentioned before through health-related activities that include lots of things like sleeping, running, ab workouts, therapy session, STI checks, etc, really any health activity you can design a verification proof off of. Those activities are private to you and they should be, so the system implements a proof generation system. This gets complicated, but the gist is you access an App on the network like a theoretical status.health for STI test history verification, that App then generates a proof you did a thing, and sends it to the network. The network then pays you for your proof and stores it under your ProfileID which is cryptographically separated from your identity.</p>

<p>Proofs that are generated are not just trophies, you can actually turn them into products you sell, and even cooler, the protocol expects you to game it. Thanks to my buddy Dakota, who explained why <a href="https://www.pathofexile.com/">Path of Exile</a> works: you can always evolve your build and break it in new ways, and it stays fair. That’s how genetic adaptation landed in Autophage. Burn tokens, unlock new traits, specialize. If you’re a marathon runner, show your trait stack and earn multiples on running activities. If you care about privacy, share less, and still get paid. The more you adapt, the better your rewards. Apps and businesses pay to issue, verify, and use the protocol. Users just access and build reputation. All fees are in USDC. No protocol token games. If you spam, you get cut out. If you contribute, you get paid.</p>

<p>The protocol uses zkVM orchestration for proof verification - basically allowing apps to verify you did something health-related without ever seeing your actual data.</p>

<h2 id="onlyfans-for-proof">onlyfans for proof</h2>

<p>The protocol flips health data ownership just like OnlyFans did for the porn industry. Not only can apps help you verify activity, but they can also help you sell health proofs you generate through the marketplace. Buyers could include individuals or businesses for things like medical research or post-hookup should a partner get anxious about your testing history. Anonymous marathon proof sells for $10-20 baseline. Reveal your ProfileID so buyers can follow your journey, earn 50-100% more. Show customizable traits your spec’d in proving you’re an endurance specialist, command $50+ per proof. Therapy consistency, workout streaks, STI tests, sleep quality, whatever you track becomes a potential product you can benefit from.</p>

<p>The marketplace has three layers. Individuals buy proofs from each other to study real health journeys or verify fitness, kind of like peacocks and their feathers. Someone training for their first marathon buys experienced runners’ proofs to understand pacing. Dating apps verify STI status without storing medical records. Research organizations purchase anonymous population data at scale. A university studying exercise patterns might buy 10,000 anonymous running proofs for $50,000. Every transaction protects privacy through zero-knowledge separation. Buyers get verification without identity. Sellers get paid without exposure.</p>

<p>You control the terms. List anonymous and stay completely private. Build a following around your ProfileID without revealing your name. Display specialized traits when expertise pays. The protocol takes 12% to fund The Reservoir. Apps that verified your activity get 5%. You keep 88% in USDC. Cash for health receipts. Privacy settings determine price. The market decides value. You own what you earn.</p>

<h2 id="proposals-and-upgrades-as-a-real-job">proposals and upgrades as a real job</h2>

<p>The protocol treats development like a real market. You can ship any improvement that makes the system better. New proof mechanisms for different health activities, stronger privacy circuits, reputation algorithms that catch gaming, incentive curves that balance rewards. When apps adopt your code and it processes real health data, you capture value through integration fees, performance bounties, usage royalties, and security rewards. Early simulations show active developers earning $30-90k annually just from base activity, but that’s conservative math. The real opportunity is building critical infrastructure that thousands of apps depend on, like npm packages that print money. No voting, no committees, no “community calls” where nothing happens. Pure market dynamics: your code gets used, you get paid. It doesn’t, you don’t. The protocol needs everything from better zkVM orchestration to ML models for health insights to integration bridges for existing systems. Each improvement creates compound value and compound earnings. It’s an economic system where protocol improvements translate directly to developer income indefinitely as the network scales.</p>

<p>Anyone can propose improvements by staking 100-5,000 tokens on specific health metrics. The protocol runs controlled experiments for 30-180 days. Hit your 5% improvement target and get your stake back plus USDC bonuses proportional to impact. Miss and The Reservoir takes your tokens. Good improvers build reputation, stake more, run bigger experiments. Stack wins and you’ve got a real career improving public health infrastructure while getting paid in real money. The network adapts through these continuous experiments, evolving based on what actually works.</p>

<h2 id="the-usdc-loop">the usdc loop</h2>

<p>Apps pay $0.10-0.20 monthly per user for verification rails. Enterprises drop $20-100 per employee wellness check. Users sell health proofs to each other with the marketplace taking 12%. All USDC flows to The Reservoir. The split: 10% for protocol development, 90% for healthcare settlements and reserves. Users earn USDC selling anonymous marathon proofs for 10 bucks or specialized genetic traits for 30. Apps compete on features while paying base infrastructure fees. Healthcare providers submit tokens and get settled in USDC at metabolic prices (essentially dynamic pricing based on the actual metabolic cost of healthcare activities). Developer improvements that get adopted earn integration fees and usage royalties. More network activity creates more fees, deeper reserves, better healthcare coverage. Your lifetime token contributions track your healthcare access rights. Decay funds the community, fees fund the infrastructure, proofs fund the users. Everything cycles through The Reservoir keeping value moving, never pooling.</p>

<h2 id="receipts-math-and-where-to-break-things">receipts, math, and where to break things</h2>

<p>The yellowpaper contains all the real math - every incentive curve, privacy proof, and system invariant. There’s also a patent filed covering the core mechanics. The protocol documentation includes code snippets, use cases, and simulation frameworks. If you can break it, send through a report to info@autophage.io.</p>

<h2 id="sims-dont-lie">sims don’t lie</h2>

<p>The Health Protocol died every time in Monte Carlo simulations. Whales accumulated or bots farmed rewards or real users quit. Classic crypto death spiral. I killed it and built Autophage with different physics. Tokens that decay prevent hoarding. Genetic traits reward specialization over capital. The Reservoir recycles value instead of letting it pool. Ran thousands of simulations with every attack vector I could imagine. Bot armies, whale cartels (lol), bank runs (omg), you name it (I prob tried it). The protocol bent but didn’t break. Value stayed distributed because decay forces circulation. Users specialized into sustainable niches. The marketplace found equilibrium prices. The Reservoir maintained reserves through fee flows. Not perfect, but the numbers finally worked. Sometimes you have to let something die to build something that can live.</p>

<h2 id="the-last-thing-ill-say-about-rocks">the last thing i’ll say about rocks</h2>

<p>Crypto built itself on hodling. Diamond hands. Never sell. Rocks don’t need food, water, or healthcare. We do. The protocol’s meme captures it: “hodl? lol. not here.” Tokens decay because life does. Value moves or dies. The protocol name Autophage comes from autophagy - the biological process where cells eat their own damaged parts to survive. For those hunting deeper secrets, Charlotte holds the key.</p>

<!-- the first clue in national treasure -->

<p><em>What if our deepest economic assumption that value should persist forever is perfectly inverted?</em></p>]]></content><author><name>97115104</name></author><category term="crypto" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="health" /><category term="web3" /><category term="zk" /><category term="startups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[why i killed my own crypto project (and built something that could actually live)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">my first failure as a startup founder</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/06/first-failure/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my first failure as a startup founder" /><published>2025-06-06T16:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-06T16:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/06/06/first-failure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/06/06/first-failure/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-wrong-co-founder">the wrong co-founder</h2>

<p>My first real mistake as a founder wasn’t about product or tech, although both did change from what they were originally. It was bringing in a friend—who was also my ex—to help build the company. I thought splitting the responsibility of running things would make it lighter, like a feather. I thought trust was enough. It isn’t. It’s like the weight that hits <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wile_E._Coyote_and_the_Road_Runner">Wile E. Coyote</a>—you can’t run your way out of it. You need more than history. You need someone who shows up every day, who wants to, and who can. Even if things are going swimmingly, there’s likely a time when they won’t, and when personalities are really under the pressure of potentially seven figures, or eight, or ten, or none—who knows. This might sound pessimistic, but it’s not. It’s a lesson in optimism and learning. You get better by going through it.</p>

<h2 id="what-i-missed">what I missed</h2>

<p>We never defined the work other than at a high level: “you take marketing and finance and corporate governance bullshit, I’ll take engineering, product, and share some of the marketing.” We didn’t decide how decisions would get made other than “we’ll always run things by each other,” or agree that building a real company is full-time—like, seriously, 3 AM every night and no Cinco de Mayo parties because the patent. Startups don’t wait for you to catch up. We should have put it in writing, apart from our Founders Agreement. We should have actually weighed and measured the Founders Agreement, not signed it on our mobile devices on a whim thinking it would never <em>really</em> matter. I should have said what I wanted. He should have said what he wanted. We should have talked about our “fuck you numbers.” It was my first time doing this without a team, or a big company’s money, or someone else’s rules, so I can’t blame myself. I can’t blame him. Or the situation, or really anything. I can just learn, and share my experience so others don’t, hopefully, repeat the same errors in their founder journey.</p>

<h2 id="what-he-brought">what he brought</h2>

<p>He was ambitious and hungry. He wanted to be CEO. We actually fought about who would be CEO in the end. He wanted to be the one walking into the room as the leader of a big company, the one selling it to people, the one in front. He had what I didn’t—the desire to be seen, to be admired. I prefer to do things in the background and admire my work from afar. He helped with incorporating the company, and writing (because I am obviously bad at writing). He was great at scheduling things, talking with potential customers and investors off the clock, and getting folks excited. But he just didn’t have enough time. He wasn’t willing to take the same risk, mostly because he isn’t as privileged as I am and isn’t willing to lose it all, which I get. But that’s what it takes. I now have to be a different person, and for that I am thankful, because I am stronger. But it was painful to lose him—he mattered.</p>

<h2 id="when-it-turned">when it turned</h2>

<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_4DmuODdSGVrdFsH3eMu758Moij-I_vp/view">The patent</a>. By the time it was ready for another person to review, it was like 60 pages. I had written it, read it, and iterated on it at least a hundred times—or that’s what it felt like—by the time it was ready to be submitted. All that needed to happen was his eyes, confirmation, and a plus-one. But that was also the same day as Cinco de Mayo, and the fun was enticing for us both. I didn’t buckle and submitted that night—he went for a marg. It was the beginning of the end for our co-founder-ness.</p>

<p>Around that same time, I pitched a licensing deal where I would own the patent and the company would lease it for free—unless I was no longer at the company, at which point it would have to pay for it. He said it wouldn’t be good for the company. What I found out later was that he started second-guessing my motives. I get it. What was really happening is that my nine-hour days felt worth more than the 50% of the company I owned, and if I was putting in all the real work, I wanted a bigger upside. In reality, I pitched that as a cry for his attention, to help course correct, and hopefully get more “work” for the company out of it.</p>

<p>My error here was missing that he just didn’t have the time. He was working three other jobs after all. I was naive. I could have been kinder, nicer, less aggressive even. He mentioned some of the things I said were emotionally abusive. This was hard for me to hear, but he’s probably right in some ways. I can be mean when I am tired, hungry, and at the end of my proverbial leash. I needed him to help correct me and bring me back down to normal. He was my opposite after all. I didn’t realize that it was unrealistic to expect this from a business partner—and maybe even from a friend. I have to regulate myself, and make sure I take time to garden my body and my brain, not just the business. That lesson is one I’ll take with me forever, and I thank him for that.</p>

<h2 id="how-it-ended">how it ended</h2>

<p>The real ending was in Dolores Park. We sat and talked a bit, both of us nervous—well, I was nervous, he was probably just mad, because it was nothing like when we first met at that club on his 23rd or 24th birthday, I forget which. In some ways, it felt like the last time we’d ever meet. The conversation ended with me offering that dinner I owed him for helping me sell some jewelry I needed to fund my lifestyle and the startup (that damn patent was expensive). He agreed to the dinner, after which he walked home, looking a little lighter in his step free of me and the startup, to the puppy we used to share and his beautiful boyfriend I sometimes wish was still me. I took some solace in the idea that we were still friends, but now, maybe we aren’t? Ugh, running a company is hard. Don’t do it with your friends, ex-lovers, or family. Be warned.</p>

<h2 id="what-founders-really-need-to-know">what founders really need to know</h2>

<p>When you start out, you think you know how hard it’s going to be. I didn’t. The real test isn’t the product, or the legal forms, or the late nights—it’s everything that happens to you, and who you become in the process.</p>

<p>I used to do ops and product, and engineering, and recruiting and everything. I thought I knew it all. In reality, it couldn’t be more different. Paying taxes, statements of information, articles of incorporation, a million contracts, boilerplate that isn’t code—the whole thing is dizzying. I was hoping he’d take this on, but I now see the value in knowing how to do it all myself, and I see the new me in it. I read every single line of a contract, the bylaws, the license agreement for the patent, and you should too. It’s what dictates the next 10+ years of your life as a founder, and maybe more if you believe the folks in <a href="https://www.foundervsinvestor.com/">“Founder vs. Investor.”</a></p>

<p>You don’t see it until you do, and it is worth it even though it doesn’t feel like it. Or at least I hope it is.</p>

<h2 id="for-the-record">for the record</h2>

<p>Thinking about it more, I don’t actually know if any of this was worth the cost. Losing a friend, especially an ex, never feels worth it. If I could do it again, I’d have shared my needs as a founder. I’d have explained that I am not the same person in business as I am in our friendship, or as I was in our relationship. I am somehow much stronger, but also much weaker in other ways. Please, <em>dear reader</em>, take note if you end up working with a friend or ex or family member: make the clear distinction between the <em>you</em> that is a business person, the <em>you</em> that is a friend, and the <em>you</em> that is in the clubs or when you see a cute boy, because they are all versions of you that show up at different times, and you better bet they haven’t seen the business you yet.</p>

<p>Some days, the work is worth every cost. Other days, it isn’t. I’m still here, still learning, and still doing the job, and I plan to until this thing really does <a href="https://status.health/">reduce STI transmission rates</a> and for me, that’s enough.</p>

<h2 id="letter-to-you-and-to-me">letter to you, and to me</h2>

<p>You saw something in this before I did.<br />
You helped turn it from idea to company.<br />
You called out my blind spots.<br />
You pulled me back in when I wanted out.<br />
I wanted us both all-in, building something that mattered.<br />
We didn’t get there.</p>

<p>I hope your part of this means something—whether or not we ever talk again.<br />
I hope you know you mattered, even when things fell apart.</p>

<p>To myself:<br />
Keep building.<br />
Remember where you started.<br />
Don’t lose more than you have to.<br />
If it works, let it mean something for both of us.</p>]]></content><author><name>97115104</name></author><category term="startups" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[the wrong co-founder]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">i’m probably going to launch a new cryptocurrency in addition to status.health…🙄</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/31/The-$HEALTH-Token/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="i’m probably going to launch a new cryptocurrency in addition to status.health…🙄" /><published>2025-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/31/The-$HEALTH-Token</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/31/The-$HEALTH-Token/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="nobody-else-is-going-to-fix-this-mess-for-us">nobody else is going to fix this mess for us</h2>

<p>If you read my <a href="https://97115104.com/2025/05/13/hello-world/">hello world post</a>, you already know I’m a techie, but you can probably also guess I’m not in this for tech’s sake—and I’m even less of a fan of breathless “we’re disrupting X!” manifestos. In a world where even Trump has a meme coin, the bar for “launching a token” is officially on the floor. So, here’s where I stand: I’m probably going to launch a new cryptocurrency—not because I want my face on a billboard (actually that would freak me out), but because after years of wrestling with health tech, incentives, and privacy, I keep running into the same broken machinery and nobody else seems interested in fixing it.</p>

<p>Lately, this has gotten a lot more personal. I was fired for not being a “cultural fit”—which, in plain English, meant I wouldn’t work weekends for my boss. I just didn’t care enough at the time, but am now writing this at 2 a.m. on a Saturday—#ironic #iconic. Anyways, since going independent, I’ve landed squarely in the same healthcare mess as countless freelancers, gig workers, and marginalized folks: sky-high costs, awful coverage, and almost no meaningful support for prevention. Throw in my own ongoing battles with STIs (yes, plural), and I’ve had a front-row seat to just how neglected and underfunded prevention really is.</p>

<p>The big “solutioneers”—Kaiser, the government, insurance barons—are either too massive to move, too tangled up in lobbyist interests, or fundamentally structured to maintain the status quo. Insurance providers, especially, have incentives that run completely counter to most people’s real needs. So here I am: personal prevention meets a funding crisis—a weirdly perfect storm for someone stubborn enough (and just well-placed enough) to try building something new. I’m not here for vanity or hype (eww!). I’m here because the system’s busted, the usual players aren’t stepping up, and, for better or worse, I might just be in the right spot to do something about it.</p>

<h2 id="why-seriously-why">why? (seriously, why?)</h2>

<p>Short version: the incentives in healthcare are upside down, and no amount of dashboards, SaaS contracts, or “secure” portals are going to fix that. If you’ve ever tried to prove you got tested, vaccinated, or did literally anything responsible, you know the drill: fill out a form, log into yet another portal, get a PDF for your trouble, and hope it doesn’t end up in some vendor’s next data breach. If you actually want to be rewarded for doing the right thing? Good luck. The system pays when you get sick, not when you stay healthy.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, prevention is a cost center, not a business model. Nobody wants to fund it, even though <a href="https://odphp.health.gov/news/202401/prevention-still-best-medicine">it’s the only thing that actually works</a> in the long run. The few times you are “incentivized,” it’s either a spammy sweepstakes or a $10 Amazon card—never enough to matter, never enough to make it feel like your effort is valued. And through it all, you’re handing over more data than you’re comfortable with, for less and less in return.</p>

<p>Most people shrug and move on. I apparently have a higher tolerance for banging my head against the wall than most, so here we are.</p>

<h2 id="what-the-hell-would-this-even-look-like">what the hell would this even look like?</h2>

<p>I don’t want to build another “health app.” I want to build a protocol—a new set of rails that flips the incentives, rewards prevention, and makes privacy the default, not the exception. Imagine being able to prove you did the right thing (got tested, got a vaccine, whatever) without having to share your entire life story, or trust yet another startup with your data. Imagine a system where healthy behavior is actually worth something, and where the risk of participation is less than the risk of doing nothing.</p>

<p>If you’re rolling your eyes, I get it. I’m skeptical too. But I’d rather try and fail than keep waiting for someone else to get it right.</p>

<h2 id="incentives-for-humans-not-robots">incentives: for humans, not robots</h2>

<p>Let’s be honest: most “health incentives” are either so trivial they’re meaningless, or so convoluted you need to be an actuary to figure them out. I want to design something that works with how actual people behave—not how some product manager thinks they <em>should</em> behave.</p>

<p>Here’s what that means in practice: You get a tangible, real reward for verified healthy actions—not just a pat on the back. If you show up for regular testing or take other preventive action, you accrue value, not “points” that expire or can only be redeemed for branded swag. If you miss a test, the system forgives you up to a point; streaks and bonuses decay gently, not instantly, because life happens and the protocol recognizes that. Incentives are transparent and non-punitive: you can see exactly how rewards are calculated, and the most value accrues to those who are consistent, not those who can game the system. Points accrue for everyone, regardless of whether you know how to use a crypto wallet. If you want to stay in normie mode, fine—your rewards are just as real, and you can convert them to tokens whenever you want. There are no casino vibes, no “spin the wheel,” no loss aversion tricks—just a persistent, steady nudge toward better habits.</p>

<p>The reward structure isn’t just “do X, get Y.” It’s a system that recognizes effort and continuity, not just perfection. Miss a test window because you had a rough month? You don’t get the digital equivalent of a dunce cap. Instead, your rewards taper off—gently. I want this system to actually <em>work</em> for real people, not just people who never miss a checkup or who have a spreadsheet for their wellness routine.</p>

<p>And this isn’t just about individuals—if organizations, clinics, or even entire communities want to participate, there’s a pathway for that too (with proportional reward, without compromising privacy). The upside is that the system gets more robust as more entities join, and the incentives don’t get diluted into oblivion just because more people are doing the right thing. If anything, it’s the opposite: the more people and orgs that participate, the more sustainable and valuable the entire protocol becomes.</p>

<h2 id="utility-not-a-speculative-defi-coin">utility: not a speculative DeFi coin</h2>

<p>$HEALTH is a utility token, not a speculative asset. You won’t find it on DeFi exchanges or liquidity pools at launch, and there won’t be any token trading, yield farming, or pump-and-dump opportunities (sorry, not sorry). The entire point is to provide token infrastructure at the application layer—enabling products like <a href="https://status.health">status.health</a> to reward prevention and healthy behavior, support governance, and fund public health via community grants. It isn’t meant to be a “number go up” coin or a vehicle for speculation. The goal is to create a circular economy where healthy actions are directly rewarded, and community health initiatives can be sustainably funded. If your main question is “wen Binance?” you’re definitely in the wrong place.</p>

<p>What does that utility actually look like? In practice, $HEALTH tokens are earned by taking real preventive health actions—like regular testing or verification—through apps such as status.health. You can use those tokens to unlock premium features, participate in protocol governance, stake to help secure the network, or support local health initiatives via dontations. Most of this activity happens directly within the apps themselves, not on external exchanges, and is focused on rewarding participation and fueling public goods. As more partners and integrations come online, $HEALTH will serve as the backbone for new health-focused tools, transparent incentives, and grants—all designed to keep the ecosystem aligned around real-world outcomes, not speculation.</p>

<h2 id="governance-decentralize-only-when-it-makes-sense">governance: decentralize only when it makes sense</h2>

<p>Let’s talk about decentralization. I’ve been around enough “DAOs” to know that most of them are just group chats with a multisig and a lot of vibes. Decentralization is great—<em>when there’s actually something to decentralize</em>. Until then, it’s a distraction.</p>

<p>My approach is pretty simple: $HEALTH starts out centralized because, frankly, someone has to do the work and make the decisions. That means I’m responsible for the roadmap, the bugs, the (hopefully rare) drama, and the general direction. But here’s the difference: as <em>actual</em> usage grows, as the protocol matures, and as more real people and organizations rely on it, governance and control will transfer—gradually, and transparently—to the community.</p>

<p>There are clear, metric-based thresholds for when governance hands off—these aren’t arbitrary, and you’ll be able to see them, track progress, and know what’s coming. Governance isn’t just about voting on proposals; it’s about funding public goods, supporting integrations, and making sure incentives stay aligned as the ecosystem evolves. Quadratic funding will ensure that many small contributors have more power than a few whales. If usage drops or the protocol gets gamed, decentralization slows or pauses—there’s no “one-way door” to chaos, and no DAO just for the sake of optics. The rules, formulas, and transition points are all public, so if you want to critique them, propose something better, or just follow along, you’ll have every tool you need. I’m committed to keeping the governance process as transparent as possible: you’ll know who’s making decisions, why they’re being made, and how to get involved if you care enough to show up. And, real talk—if nobody uses the thing, or if it turns into another DAO meme, I’d rather pull the plug than pretend it’s “community-led.” Governance is earned, not declared.</p>

<p>Here’s a thing I’ve learned: persistent skeptics and critics are actually invaluable. People who don’t just clap along but keep showing up with feedback (good or brutal)—those are the folks I want in governance. In fact, if you keep at it long enough, you might just end up on my “persistent people to hire” list. You know who you are.</p>

<p>I’m not interested in “community theater.” I want real, earned decentralization, with skin in the game and accountability. If that sounds too slow or not “Web3 enough” for you, there are plenty of Discords out there waiting for new mods.</p>

<h2 id="is-it-open-source">is it open source?</h2>

<p>This is where I usually get hate mail from the free software crowd, so let me be clear: I love open source. Most of what I make is MIT-licensed, and I strongly believe in sharing tools that help people build. But with $HEALTH, I’m being careful. Some things will be public from the start: the <a href="https://healthprotocol.network/yp">yellowpaper</a>, the math, all incentive formulas, and selected SDKs and reference components. I want people to be able to audit the core mechanisms, see how rewards are calculated, and follow the logic behind the scenes.</p>

<p>But not everything will be open—at least not right away. Why? Sometimes, it’s about protecting security while things are new and fragile. Sometimes, it’s about giving the project a chance to mature before it gets forked into oblivion or spammed by bots. Sometimes, it’s just that I’m still working out the kinks and don’t want to ship garbage into the wild. If you have a legit reason to ask for access, reach out and make your case. I’m open to collaboration and feedback, especially from folks who want to make the protocol better (or who spot problems I missed).</p>

<p>If you want to see what’s public, check out <a href="https://github.com/97115104">github.com/97115104</a> for my stuff and <a href="https://github.com/statusdothealth">github.com/statusdothealth</a> for the status.health side. If it’s not there, it’s not open (yet or ever). If that’s a deal breaker for you, I get it. But I’d rather build something that works and is safe before opening every door and letting the whole world poke holes in it. If you want to be part of that process, you know where to find me.</p>

<h2 id="whats-next-the-real-roadmap-for-better-or-worse">what’s next? (the real roadmap, for better or worse)</h2>

<p>Here’s where I stand: this is still an experiment. Patent’s pending (because lawyers need to eat), and now that both <a href="https://status.health/">status.health</a> and <a href="https://healthprotocol.network/">healthprotocol.network</a> are live (plus the yellowpaper is finally finished), I can actually start building the real MVP. Everything is still fragile and changing fast. For anyone actually curious about what’s ahead, here’s the roadmap:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Building the MVP for real-world use (through status.health):</strong> Since I run both status.health and the $HEALTH Protocol, the first version of the MVP will launch through <a href="https://status.health/">status.health</a>—but only for those who sign up for the beta (<a href="https://form.typeform.com/to/Ii3HSlEH?typeform-source=status.health">sign up here</a>). Making it generally accessible will take real money and a lot of development time, so don’t expect it overnight. This isn’t just a demo for crypto insiders—the goal is a product where privacy and incentives work for normal humans, not just blockchain hobbyists.</li>
  <li><strong>Applying for grants:</strong> Server bills aren’t paid in tokens (yet), so I’ll be applying for grants to help with ongoing development and infrastructure costs. The plan is to work with protocol foundations like the Ethereum Foundation, Web3 Foundation, and similar organizations, as well as explore on-chain treasuries and ecosystem funds that support public goods and experimental projects in the crypto space.</li>
  <li><strong>status.health as first customer:</strong> I’m working on status.health and the $HEALTH Protocol concurrently—status.health is the first customer of the $HEALTH Protocol, and hopefully not the last. The idea is to prove the infrastructure actually solves a real problem. Over time, I want to see many more apps and orgs using $HEALTH’s rails, powered by open APIs and community grants.</li>
  <li><strong>Governance and analytics:</strong> As the protocol grows, transparency grows too. Usage, impact, funding flows, and governance transitions will all be visible in real time. No hiding behind “coming soon”—if it’s working (or failing), everyone will see it.</li>
  <li><strong>Full decentralization (if earned):</strong> If this thing gains real traction, governance and control will move out of my hands and into the community’s, with clear, published thresholds and rules. Not by vibes, but by actual adoption and contribution. If it doesn’t earn that, I’m not going to pretend otherwise.</li>
  <li><strong>Iteration and humility:</strong> If the experiment blows up in my face, I’ll say so. If something’s not working, I’ll pivot or kill it. If you have feedback, ideas, or want to get involved, I’m open. If you want to sit on the sidelines and throw tomatoes, that’s fine too—I’ve got a thick skin.</li>
</ol>

<p>The bottom line: I’m not building this for a quick exit, a headline, or a token pump. I’m building it because I want a world where prevention and privacy aren’t afterthoughts. If that sounds interesting, follow along, contribute, or just lurk and watch.</p>

<p>If you want the technical receipts, actual mechanics, or just want to see how weird my sense of humor gets when writing about cryptoeconomics, the <a href="https://healthprotocol.network/yp">yellowpaper is here</a>. If you’re feeling especially masochistic, you can also read <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_4DmuODdSGVrdFsH3eMu758Moij-I_vp/view">the patent</a>—which is way more painful to read (and was to write).</p>]]></content><author><name>97115104</name></author><category term="crypto" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="health" /><category term="web3" /><category term="zk" /><category term="startups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[nobody else is going to fix this mess for us]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hello world</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/13/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hello world" /><published>2025-05-13T10:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-13T10:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/05/13/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/05/13/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction-to-this-blog">introduction to this blog</h2>

<p>The name is Austin Harshberger and this is my personal blog site. It contains arbitrary thoughts on various topics and information about things I build. While I don’t profess to be an oracle, I do hope there’s some helpful insight in my sharing of what I’ve learned that would be useful for others. If it is indeed useful or not is up to <em>you</em> as The Reader.</p>

<h2 id="about-me">about me</h2>

<p>I’m a <a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/techie">techie</a> located in San Francisco, currently in my early 30s. I accidentally became a self-taught engineer after dropping out of a mostly failed attempt at preparation for law school because I was lucky enough to get noticed at an Apple store I was working at, after creating an automation script, that streamlined store operations using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bash_(Unix_shell)">Bash</a>. Apple liked it enough to hire me at 19 with no degree or previous experience as an engineer and moved me to Cupertino with a sign-on bonus. I was there for a few months before deciding it wasn’t for me. Thankfully they didn’t ask for the bonus back. After that, I built some Android apps, ironic purposefully, and took an immersive course in UX design before getting a job doing customer service, with some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moonlighting">moonlighting</a> as a developer, at a place called IDEO. I was there for a bit before getting a job at GitHub, where I was long enough to see the Microsoft acquisition. I left GitHub to join the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web3">Web3</a> space, first at Coinbase, then NEAR, Parity Technologies, and finally Aleo where my focus was on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zero_knowledge">zero-knowledge cryptography</a>.</p>

<p>Probably thanks to my Mom, people generally tend to like me so I progressed through my career in a vertical-and-up fashion, from engineering to recruiting, to program management, then product management. I ended my career working for other people as an engineering manager, which I thought I’d enjoy more than I actually did because it was mostly politics and I’m not the best student of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machiavellianism_(psychology)">machiavellianism</a>, in fact, quite the opposite, unfortunately. Now, thanks to a confluence of events, a good idea, and too many STIs, I am the founder of a startup called <a href="https://status.health">status.health</a> focused on improving sexual wellness and reducing STI transmission rates.</p>

<h2 id="ai-tools-and-me">ai tools and me</h2>

<p>I am an AI tools maxi and believe, strongly, that they help more than they hurt. Though, for some reason, I find mine an unpopular opinion among peers. When I reflect on it, I am reminded of the early days of every groundbreaking emerging technology: the industrial revolution, the telegram, cameras, phones, cell phones, the internet, social media, crypto, and now AI. EVERY SINGLE TIME it scares people. Luckily, I don’t scare easily and am often eager to learn something new.</p>

<p>AI tools are nowhere near as good as humans at any particular task–they are “generally” intelligent but not expert at anything regardless of how good you are at prompting them. They are much cheaper and easier to delegate to than an employee in the context of a startup or as a business owner. For consumers that fact check responses they can be more effective than search engines at following train of thought thereby enabling a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stream_of_consciousness">“stream of consciousness”</a> Siri and her ilk only wish they could deliver. As such, AI tools have their place in growing a startup, helping with learning, and other things that require specialized knowledge or a huge learning curve: programming, complex math, a new language–you name it. AI is terrible at being creative. Probably not news to most of you reading, but worth reiterating as I continue to find it annoying since I am not the best “creative” either. When making assets for products I build, it’s often the hardest task there is; I guess job security for the designers, artists, and writers out there. Congratulations.</p>

<p>I feel strongly that everyone should and probably will eventually use AI, but I also believe in being clear about when it was used. Why not just say:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>❔”I created X with an initial prompt and multiple iterations based on research. After some back-and-forth, Claude and I got X to where it is now and I am proud of it. I probably don’t know <em>everything</em> about it but I know most of it and can answer any questions you have.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Not attesting to the way X deliverable was created only impacts your reputation negatively when you inevitably get stumped answering a question about something outside your depth. It’s like a teacher calling on you in English class after you chose to spend the night playing World of Warcraft instead of reading “The Scarlet Letter.” You should have just read the thing, but short of that, letting your teacher know you played WoW instead and plan to listen to the other students’ answers to learn that way, is the next best thing.</p>

<p>In short: AI-assisted anything should be attested to (clearly marked), and so should human-generated content because it addresses two key concerns most people have: 1. a person misrepresenting work and not actually knowing what a deliverable is or does, and 2. AI’s reputation for being a human-killer vs. a human-enabler, except, of course, for the creatives. Assigning credit where credit is due is not new. It’s much like when that same English teacher insisted on annoyingly formatted in-line citations or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chicago_Manual_of_Style">Chicago style</a> for book reports.</p>

<p>To make attesting to AI-assisted work vs. that of human work easier for myself and my businesses, Claude and I created a site called <a href="https://attest.ink">attest.ink</a> which allows automated badge generation. I use attest.ink and its <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attestation">attestations</a> for almost everything I produce that has a public eye on it, and you should too. It’s free! Check it out and let me know if you have any questions or suggested improvements: <a href="mailto:info@attest.ink">info@attest.ink</a>.</p>

<h4 id="what-badge-attestations-look-like">what badge attestations look like</h4>
<!-- Add this to your blog HTML -->
<p><a href="https://attest.ink" target="_blank" class="badge-link" rel="noopener">
  <img src="https://attest.ink/assets/badges/human-generated.svg" alt="Human Generated" width="120" height="30" />
  <img src="https://attest.ink/assets/badges/chatgpt-generated.svg" alt="AI Assisted" width="120" height="30" />
  <img src="https://attest.ink/assets/badges/claude-generated.svg" alt="AI Assisted" width="120" height="30" />
  <img src="https://attest.ink/assets/badges/gemini-generated.svg" alt="AI Assisted" width="120" height="30" />
  <img src="https://attest.ink/assets/badges/midjourney-generated.svg" alt="AI Assisted" width="120" height="30" />
  <img src="https://attest.ink/assets/badges/dalle-generated.svg" alt="AI Assisted" width="120" height="30" />
</a></p>

<h4 id="for-those-who-think-one-cant-determine-if-content-is-ai-generated">for those who think one can’t determine if content is ai-generated</h4>

<p>You are wrong because, thankfully, there are a growing number of tools out there that can do. While they mostly use heuristics (educated guesses based on data), they do help “out” content where an individual is trying to claim something was generated without AI assistance. For those moments when it feels like misrepresentation might be afoot, or if you are simply curious, I found <a href="https://copyleaks.com/ai-content-detector">Copyleaks’s AI detector</a> the most useful—it even has a <a href="https://copyleaks.com/ai-content-detector/extension">Chrome extension</a>. So if you are the person being disingenuous, sorry not sorry.</p>

<h2 id="ai-and-this-blog-site">ai and this blog site</h2>

<p>Blog posts on this site are usually not AI-assisted other than for grammar and spelling checks because I am terrible at both. Blog content that is marked as human-generated is original other than that content, ideas, and interpretations are based on my analysis of other people’s works, thoughts I’ve had based on conversations with friends and family, and general content consumption–we are, after all, a product of our environment. Not dissimilar from how AI is a product of the data it has access to. While I could easily use Claude to write every post though ChatGPT is better, I think it’s more valuable to write them myself. Doing so serves as a good reminder of the time it takes to make something without AI-assistance, and it’s fun despite how grueling I find long-form writing. I will admit that I am also creating this blog and a vast majority of its posts so I can train the various AIs on my writing style, voice, and humor, since they are currently woefully bad at both due to the lack of data out there representing me. When a blog post is AI-assited, you’ll know via the attestation badge. The non-blog content on this site such as the site itself, <em>was</em> created with AI assistance because Claude is a faster engineer than I am (though not better 😉). That said, you can take solace in the fact that you are reading my thoughts, unadulterated as they may be. Look out for the “Human Generated” or “AI-Assisted” badge for clarity.</p>

<h2 id="mostly-open-source">mostly open source</h2>

<p>For the most part everything I create is under the typical open source <a href="https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT">MIT License</a>. You should feel free to use my words, my website content, and thoughts, I just ask for proper citation, e.g., <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Harshberger, A, $DATE, $BLOG-POST-NAME</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">attest.ink, A. H. $DATE</code>. The exception to this rule is anything over at status.health or where I explicitly mark something under copyright with ©. In those instances, just shoot me an email for permission or with any questions: <a href="mailto:x@97115104.com">x@97115104.com</a>.</p>

<h2 id="for-those-that-like-to-internet-stalk">for those that like to internet stalk</h2>

<p>You can find more info with a DuckDuckGo query, on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aharshbe/">LinkedIn</a>, or the bio on my startup’s website: <a href="https://status.health/team">status.health/team</a>.</p>

<h2 id="contact">contact</h2>

<p>Feel free to send through a message via <a href="mailto:x@97115104.com">email</a> or <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/aharshbe/">LinkedIn</a> or <a href="https://github.com/97115104">GitHub</a> or <a href="https://t.me/x97115104">Telegram</a>.</p>

<p><em>‘Twas nice to e-meet you, dear reader!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>97115104</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="ai" /><category term="startups" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[introduction to this blog]]></summary></entry></feed>